barcodelookup.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy | Barcode Lookup

Last modified: May 1, 2017

This Privacy Policy applies to services provided by Barcode Lookup through its website, located at www.barcodelookup.com, including subdomains, API and mobile applications (the “Services”).

By clicking “I agree” or by using the Services, you are agreeing, or if you are agreeing on behalf of an entity, the entity is agreeing, to the collection, use and disclosure of information about you as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you later disagree with the Privacy Policy, you agree to stop using the Services and contact Barcode Lookup.

We collect, use and disclose two types of information: (1) personal information, and (2) anonymous information. Personal information identifies you, such as your name and email address, while anonymous information does not identify you, such as statistical data, which we may combine with anonymous information about others.

## 1\. Personal Information

We collect all personal information you provide in connection with the Services, such as:

  * when you fill out a form, subscribe to the Services, apply to be an Affiliate or request a phone or web consultation. Personal information collected includes your first and last name, company name, website and email address, phone number, billing address and credit card information. We associate your use of the Services with your personal information, such as purchases made, data requested and returned through the Services and Affiliate ID; and
  * if you are an Affiliate, we associate your personal information with your Affiliate ID and Commissions.

Please note that the Services may require you to provide personal information in certain circumstances. A failure to provide personal information may result in certain features of the Services being unavailable to you.

## 2\. Anonymous Information

We collect anonymous information from you, which may be provided to us by a third party, including but not limited to:

  * statistical data concerning use of the Services, such as search queries, API calls and button clicks, session length, conversions and access frequency;
  * email open rates, click-through rates and other email marketing related data;
  * method of accessing the Services, such as, operating system, web browser, device type and identifier and IP address; and
  * logs, error reports and events and other diagnostic information.

Please note that while your device may allow you to turn off the collection of some of the above information, you may not be able to access all content and features of the Services.

## 3\. Use of Your Information

We use your personal and anonymous information internally for purposes including:

  * providing the Services to you and performing requests made of us;
  * to understand how you use the Services and to improve the Services;
  * to serve advertisements and other marketing and promotional purposes;
  * customer support and to inform you of changes to the Services, such as outages, suspensions or other material changes;
  * if you signed up for our newsletter or otherwise expressed interest in the Services, to contact you for promotional purposes, which you may opt-out of by clicking the link located in the email; and
  * if you provided a testimonial, we may associate it with your full name and/or company name, and use this information for marketing.

## 4\. Information Disclosure

We disclose your information outside of Barcode Lookup for the following purposes:

  * to parent companies, affiliates, subsidiaries and contractors in connection with the Services;
  * to law enforcement and other third parties in order to comply with applicable law or to protect our interests;
  * to an acquirer of Barcode Lookup or one or more of our business assets, who we may grant a right to continue to use and collect your information as set forth in the Privacy Policy.

## 5\. Third Party Services and Advertising

We disclose your information to third parties who assist us with, for example, advertising, payment processing, customer support, technical issues, tracking use of the Services and generating reports and data models. These third parties collect your information through tracking technologies, such as cookies or web beacons. For example, we participate in Google Adword® and Adsense® campaigns, and third parties may display ads and related content based on your use of the Services.

These third parties use and disclose your information pursuant to the terms of their own privacy policies, which we recommend you read before disclosing your information.

## 6\. Mobile Application Privacy

If you use our mobile application to access the Services, we may request access to your device’s camera in order to scan barcodes you direct the camera toward. Your device’s scanner reads each barcode so we may return useful product information from our database. Barcode Lookup does not collect any mobile application user’s personal information. However, we do collect Google Analytics® data from our mobile application users, which is provided to us on an anonymous basis.

Third party advertisements may be presented to you when using our mobile application, which may collect your information, such as location and device data, in order to recognize and target advertisements to you across different devices. For example, you Internet router IP address could be used to identify both your computer and a mobile device connected to the router and third parties could target advertisements to both devices based on your online behaviour. Please review section 5 above concerning third party collection and use of your information. Additionally, some devices allow users to op-out of mobile behavioral advertising through the settings menu.

## 7\. Cookies

A cookie is a file that is sent by a service through your browser to your device, if your browser is enabled to accept cookies, in order to store certain information on your device such as site preferences and search history. You have the option to disable or turn off cookies in your browser settings, which may affect your experience using the Services.

## 8\. California Do Not Track Disclosure

Do Not Track, or DNT, is a web browser setting that requests a web application to stop tracking you. When you turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, analytics companies, advertising networks, plug in providers and other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity. Currently, there is no DNT technology standard and, as a result, the Services do not respond to DNT signals.

## 9\. Accessing or Changing Information

You may contact us to obtain a copy of personal information we collected about you, which may be subject to a fee as permitted by applicable law. Additionally, you may contact us to correct or delete personal information we collected about you, except to the extent that retention is necessary for our legitimate business purposes, required by applicable law, in the control of a third party, or where correction or deletion is not technically feasible.

## 10\. Information Security, Storage and Retention

In order to prevent unauthorized access to your information we have put in place suitable physical and electronic safeguards to secure the information we collect. Your data is stored in the United States and processed by third parties in countries around the world and you authorize Barcode Lookup and third parties acting on our behalf to use and process your data in any country, which may subject your data to different legal protections than available in your home jurisdiction.

We retain your personal information until you request its deletion pursuant to section 9 above or until we no longer need it for the purposes for which it was originally collected.

## 11\. Updates

Barcode Lookup reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to modify the Privacy Policy at any time (“Updates”). Barcode Lookup shall notify you of Updates by making them available at www.barcodelookup.com. You are deemed to accept any Update by continuing to use the Services. Unless Barcode Lookup states otherwise, Updates are automatically effective 10 days after posting on www.barcodelookup.com.

## 12\. Contact Us

If you have questions or comments about the Privacy Policy please contact us at [legal@barcodelookup.com](mailto:legal@barcodelookup.com).
